<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on ZHXILIN&#39;S BLOG</title>
    <link>https://zhxilin.github.io/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on ZHXILIN&#39;S BLOG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2016–2020, zhxilin&#39;s blog; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 14:03:54 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zhxilin.github.io/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SSL certificate and nginx config</title>
      <link>https://zhxilin.github.io/post/ssl_certificate_and_nginx_config/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 14:03:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhxilin.github.io/post/ssl_certificate_and_nginx_config/</guid>
      <description>HTTP, as an application layer protocol, remains focused on presenting information, but cares less about the way this information travels from one place to another. Unfortunaly, this means that HTTP can be intercepted and potentially altered, making both the information and the information receiver vulnerable.
HTTPS protocol is an extension for HTTP. That &amp;ldquo;S&amp;rdquo; stands for Secure and it is powered by Transport Layer Secrurity(TLS), the succesor to Secure Sockets Layer(SSL).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solve Slow Access To Gitlab via ssh</title>
      <link>https://zhxilin.github.io/post/solve_slow_access_to_gitlab_via_ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 20:20:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhxilin.github.io/post/solve_slow_access_to_gitlab_via_ssh/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve deployed a custom gitlab server for my team. I found that it&amp;rsquo;s weired that when clone, pull, push or fetch codes from the gitlab server via SSH, it performs slow response times for each access. But it works perfectly via HTTPS.
After seaching sort of posts, it&amp;rsquo;s pointed that the SSH service of gitlab server enables UseDNS feature by default, which makes it slow to access via SSH.
 While it is possible to run a GitLab instance using only IP addresses, it is often beneficial to use DNS as it is easier for users and is required for HTTPS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update multiple versions of dev tools under Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://zhxilin.github.io/post/ubuntu_update_alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 15:12:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhxilin.github.io/post/ubuntu_update_alternatives/</guid>
      <description>Since different projects may require different versions of the same dev tool, we have to install multiple versions of them and provide a way for quick switch. This post introduces how to use update-alternatives command to switch dev tool versions under Ubuntu.
I will take protoc for example.
 ProjectA requires protoc 3.6.1 ProjectB requires protoc 3.17.0  Install multiple versions of protoc  Download different releases for Protocol Buffers  3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WSL2 Network Forwarding</title>
      <link>https://zhxilin.github.io/post/wsl2_network_forwarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 10:21:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhxilin.github.io/post/wsl2_network_forwarding/</guid>
      <description>With the WSL2 Released, Microsoft has made a big change on the system architecture, including changing from the default bridged network adapter to a hyper-v virtual network adapter.
The new version of WSL is built on Hyper-V, which provides independent virtual network adapter for the virtual matchine. Therefore, WSL2 cannot share the network with host directly. The work around is to forward the TCP ports of WSL2 to the host OS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s std::ios::sync_with_stdio(false) and std::cin.tie(nullptr)?</title>
      <link>https://zhxilin.github.io/post/sync_with_stdio_false_cin_tie_null/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 10:45:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhxilin.github.io/post/sync_with_stdio_false_cin_tie_null/</guid>
      <description>You may often see the following calls std::ios::sync_with_stdio(false) and std::cin.tie(nullptr) in some online judge system, such as leetcode, poj, etc. Someone would tell you that these codes are usually used to speed up the execution time. But what is the exact meanings for these codes?
1static auto _ = []() { 2 std::ios::sync_with_stdio(false); 3 std::cin.tie(nullptr); 4 return nullptr; 5}(); These two calls have different meanings that have nonthing to do with performance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
